Andrew Haven drew.haven@stanford.edu 408-982-5425

March 18, 2010

Akamai Technologies, Inc. Cambridge, MA

To whom it may concern:

I love to program. It is where I am most comfortable and at home. My work at Stanford has shown me that the future of computing will be distributed. Networks of computers will be able to deliver orders of magnitude more power than any central mainframe. Distributed computing has so many open questions and is under such active development that I expect it to be an exciting place to work over the next decade.

Distributed computing is an intriguing question because we know we have the resources available, but we need to be able to harness them such that they are flexible and scalable. Answering these questions will open up more options in our computing, allowing applications to be distributed across continents and automatically scale to handle load, all while maintaining low latencies and security. These are problems I want to help tackle.

My experience has taught me that creating extensible, maintainable systems is paramount for any large project. The best way to tackle complexity is to reduce that complexity using powerful abstractions. I pride myself on writing readable code and developing coherent APIs. I am fluent with both object-oriented and functional programming. I am seeking to work on even larger code bases so that I can see how my techniques scale, how they fail, and how others have overcome the obstacles before me.

My vocational background is largely in systems administration and web programming. However, I have been programming since I was 10 and have never lost the love of burying myself in an afternoon of debugging and I yearn to have more code in my job. In order to improve my programming I am currently working towards a Masters in CS at Stanford in my off hours. Working while I study allows me to immediately and directly apply the things I learn, and gives me a context for everything I hear in the classroom.

I look forward to working with the original content distribution systems company and harnessing the power of highly distributed code. I hope to hear from you soon as I am eager to start a new chapter in my career.

Sincerely,

Andrew Haven

Andrew Haven

drew.hav en@gmail.com // 650-967-1827

EXPERIENCE

2006-present	Computer Analyst Stanford University
	 Supported a department consisting of ~50 users and many heterogeneous systems.
	 Worked independently designing and developing projects.
	 Wrote software for driving experiments using Matlab and C.
	 Designed and developed MVC web applications using for time tracking, scheduling, and presentation evaluation.
	 Setup, maintained, tested and monitored file and web servers for each lab.
	 Administered private network of about 30 systems with centralized logins, networked file systems, and centralized licencing.
	 Designed and implemented a multi-tier backup system.
2006	Web Developer Infospider
	 Developed CRM, CMS and flat websites for clients.
	• Assisted designers with SEO.
2005-2006	Freelance Web Developer
	 Worked directly with clients to determine project scope and specifications.
	• Designed and developed two e-commerce web sites for small businesses.
2005	Contract Cable Monkey Streamline Communications
	 Assisted with the setup and tear down of network infrastructure surrounding events at the San Jose Convention Center.
	 Provided help desk support to customers at the convention center.
EDUCATION	
2008-present	M.S. Computer Science (in progress) Stanford University through SCPD
	Focus on software theory
2001-2005	B.S. Applied Physics University of California, Santa Cruz
	Focus on computational physics Minor in mathematics Thesis on genetic algorithms for high dimensional optimization problems
SKILLS	
Dev elopment	C, C++, Haskell, PHP, Perl, Ruby, Javascript, SQL, SVN, Git
Web	Apache, MySQL, Ruby on Rails, Mongrel, HTML, CSS
Systems Administration	Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Solaris Services: NIS, NFS, ZFS, Samba, CIFS/SMB, DNS, NAT, HTTP, TCP/IP